<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-07-19T16:07:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Carina Veil</title><subtitle>Carina Veil is a postdoc at Stanford University, where she works on control algorithms for soft robots.
</subtitle><author><name>Carina Veil</name><email>cveil@posteo.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Attending at EMBC in Copenhagen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025-07-14-embc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Attending at EMBC in Copenhagen" /><published>2025-07-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-07-16T14:19:12+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/embc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025-07-14-embc/"><![CDATA[<p>I am attending the <a href="https://embc.embs.org/2025/">47th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering Medicine and Biology Society</a> in Copenhagen, Denmark, this week.
Our three papers are</p>
<ul>
  <li>“BlaVeS: A Novel Hand-Labeled Dataset for Improved Bladder Vessel Segmentation with Modified U-Net” by Franziska Krauß. This work tackles the challenges of variable lighting and tissue deformation in endoscopy by proposing a robust U-Net-based model with attention mechanisms, achieving state-of-the-art performance for bladder vessel segmentation. Make sure to check out our corresponding dataset <a href="https://darus.uni-stuttgart.de/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.18419/DARUS-4763">here</a> — the first publicly available dataset for blood vessel segmentation in urinary bladder endoscopy images!</li>
  <li>“Multiphysical Tumor Tissue Modeling for Improved Multimodal Sensor-Based Diagnostics” by Matthias Ege. We introduce a comprehensive tissue model that simulates the electro-mechanical behavior of bladder tumors to generate synthetic, multimodal datasets—laying the foundation for better sensor fusion and real-time tissue classification during surgery.</li>
  <li>“Tumor Margin Estimation through Simulated Impedivity Mappings Using a Multielectrode Sensor Array” by Zoltan Lovasz. Impedance sensor arrays can help to detect tumorous cell aggregations. This study presents a novel impedivity mapping approach that significantly improves tumor margin estimation accuracy over traditional impedance maps, particularly for complex tumor scenarios.</li>
</ul>

<p>Furthermore, I am co-chairing a few sessions, and we are organizing a German EMBS Chapter Meetup.</p>]]></content><author><name>Carina Veil</name><email>cveil@posteo.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am attending the 47th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering Medicine and Biology Society in Copenhagen, Denmark, this week. Our three papers are “BlaVeS: A Novel Hand-Labeled Dataset for Improved Bladder Vessel Segmentation with Modified U-Net” by Franziska Krauß. This work tackles the challenges of variable lighting and tissue deformation in endoscopy by proposing a robust U-Net-based model with attention mechanisms, achieving state-of-the-art performance for bladder vessel segmentation. Make sure to check out our corresponding dataset here — the first publicly available dataset for blood vessel segmentation in urinary bladder endoscopy images! “Multiphysical Tumor Tissue Modeling for Improved Multimodal Sensor-Based Diagnostics” by Matthias Ege. We introduce a comprehensive tissue model that simulates the electro-mechanical behavior of bladder tumors to generate synthetic, multimodal datasets—laying the foundation for better sensor fusion and real-time tissue classification during surgery. “Tumor Margin Estimation through Simulated Impedivity Mappings Using a Multielectrode Sensor Array” by Zoltan Lovasz. Impedance sensor arrays can help to detect tumorous cell aggregations. This study presents a novel impedivity mapping approach that significantly improves tumor margin estimation accuracy over traditional impedance maps, particularly for complex tumor scenarios.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Presenting at ACC in Denver</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025-06-30-acc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presenting at ACC in Denver" /><published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-06-30T21:48:03+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/acc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025-06-30-acc/"><![CDATA[<p>I will be presenting research from my postdoc at University of Stuttgart &amp; UC San Diego at the <a href="https://acc2025.a2c2.org">American Control Conference (ACC)</a> in Denver, CO. Drop by session TuB18 Estimation and Control of Distributed Parameter Systems I on Tuesday after lunch to meet me and my co-authors Miroslav Krstic, Mamadou Diagne, Iasson Karafyllis, Cenk Demir, and Oliver Sawodny.</p>

<p>I will also attend the workshop <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/acc-physics-informed-learning">Physics-Informed Machine Learning in Control</a> on Monday, and am really looking forward to connecting with people working on learning-based control. See you soon!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/news/acc.png" alt="ACC" width="600" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Carina Veil</name><email>cveil@posteo.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I will be presenting research from my postdoc at University of Stuttgart &amp; UC San Diego at the American Control Conference (ACC) in Denver, CO. Drop by session TuB18 Estimation and Control of Distributed Parameter Systems I on Tuesday after lunch to meet me and my co-authors Miroslav Krstic, Mamadou Diagne, Iasson Karafyllis, Cenk Demir, and Oliver Sawodny.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Featured on the Research Spotlight by IEEE RAS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025-05-22-featured-ieee-ras/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Featured on the Research Spotlight by IEEE RAS" /><published>2025-05-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-06-30T21:48:03+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/featured-ieee-ras</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025-05-22-featured-ieee-ras/"><![CDATA[<p>I was featured as <strong>Researcher of the month</strong> by the <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/tc-on-robot-control-ieee-ras/posts/?feedView=all">Technical Committee on Robot Control</a>  of the IEEE Robotics and Automation Society! Find the entire interview <a href="https://ieee-ras-robot-control.github.io/spotlights/carina-veil-may2025/">here</a>.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/news/ieee-ras-spotlight.jpeg" alt="IEEE Research Spotlight" width="600" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Carina Veil</name><email>cveil@posteo.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was featured as Researcher of the month by the Technical Committee on Robot Control of the IEEE Robotics and Automation Society! Find the entire interview here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Member of NextCom by CSS for 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025-02-01-nextcom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Member of NextCom by CSS for 2025" /><published>2025-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-27T03:23:17+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nextcom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025-02-01-nextcom/"><![CDATA[<p>I officially became the <strong>Communications Co-Chair</strong> of <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/css-nextcom/">NextCom</a>, a committee formed by the IEEE Control System Society (CSS) to support and guide students, early career researchers, and young professionals along their way to becoming the next generation of established control systems engineers and researchers.</p>

<p>Follow us on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/nextcom-by-css/">LinkedIn</a> to stay up-to-date, and check out the <em>Meet the leaders</em> posts.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/news/nextcom-meet-leaders.jpeg" alt="LinkedIn Post" width="600" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Carina Veil</name><email>cveil@posteo.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I officially became the Communications Co-Chair of NextCom, a committee formed by the IEEE Control System Society (CSS) to support and guide students, early career researchers, and young professionals along their way to becoming the next generation of established control systems engineers and researchers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chair of the IEEE EMBS Germany Chapter for 2025-2026</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025-01-01-embs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chair of the IEEE EMBS Germany Chapter for 2025-2026" /><published>2025-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-27T03:23:17+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/embs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025-01-01-embs/"><![CDATA[<p>I was elected to be the <strong>Chair of the IEEE EMBS Germany Chapter</strong> for the 2025-2026 term, along with Vice-Chair Nicolai Spicher, Treasurer Jannis Hagenah, and Secretary Andre Luka Çakici.</p>

<p>The IEEE Engineering Medicine and Biology Society is the world’s largest society of biomedical engineers with approximately 10,000 members from 97 countries around the world. In Germany, the EMBS is represented by the Germany Section Chapter with approximately 250 members and several student chapters.</p>

<p>Follow us on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/embs-ger/about/">LinkedIn</a> to stay up-to-date.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/news/embs-germany.jpeg" alt="Visit in Göttingen" width="600" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Carina Veil</name><email>cveil@posteo.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was elected to be the Chair of the IEEE EMBS Germany Chapter for the 2025-2026 term, along with Vice-Chair Nicolai Spicher, Treasurer Jannis Hagenah, and Secretary Andre Luka Çakici.]]></summary></entry></feed>